MANJELLAH **AWUOR OKELLO**

CONTACT

Address:

42082 00100 Nairobi

Phone:

+254715636613

Email:

manjellahawuor@gmail.com

LANGUAGES

English Swahili

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Experienced Quality Assurance, Quality Control plus regulatory affairs with a demonstrated history of working in the consumer goods industry. Skilled in Quality System, Hazard Analysis and Critical Control Points (HACCP) and Food Safety. Strong quality assurance and food research professional with a BSc Food Science and technology from University of Nairobi.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Kenya

June2019 to date Quality Assurance Executive, Trufoods limited, Nairobi, Kenya Responsibilities:

- Ensure compliance with all relevant legislation and company policy pertaining to Occupational Health, Workplace Safety, Product safety, Quality and Environmental practices.
- Formulate quality policies and programs and provide guidance and feedback to production
- Analyze quality control test results and communicate quality control information to all relevant organizational departments. outside vendors, or contractors.
- Liaise with the relevant departments to achieve legislative compliance to meet company objectives and mitigate risk.
- Develop, organize and supervise applications of the comprehensive quality and food safety programs.
- Supervise, host, or conduct internal and external audits. Follow up with action plans.
- Planning and execution of mock Traceability recalls
- Coordinate activities which enforce quality improvements
- Document, investigate and respond to customer complaints.
- Reviewing status reports from team managers and taking appropriate actions accordingly and Seeking feedback from management when and wherever necessary.

August 2017 to April 2019 Assistant quality control, Manji food industries limited, Nairobi,

- Responsibilities: Responsible for compliance expertise in all company standards and policies, external food compliance related laws, legislations, regulations
 - Implementation of quality and food safety standards in (packaging materials and finished goods warehouse) i.e. HACCP, GMP/GHP, allergen management, traceability standard, physical hazards management standard etc.
 - Ensure compliance to established product quality standards in packing and finished goods management.

- Support Laboratory Technologist in sampling and testing of incoming raw materials and packaging materials.
- Work with Technical Services to manage new product/packaging trials/experimental projects and deliver reports as required.
- Participate in quality and food safety Internal and external audits.
- Take part in refresher and induction training of Factory workers in quality and food safety procedures as well as work instructions supporting process compliance.
- Assist in planning and execution of mock Traceability recalls

April 2017 – July 2017

Management trainee, Manji food industries limited, Nairobi, Kenya

Responsibilities:

- Ensuring GMP/GHP is implemented at the site and extended to visitors and contractors.
- Planning and implementation of internal quality and safety awareness.
- Managing shifts on my own, Documenting and posting of daily Quality assurance reports.
- Ensuring Implementation and coordinate all the activities associated with the plant's GMP, GHP and Pest Control and Quality internal audits.
- Responsible for Quality inspection and in process Monitoring.
- Documenting and filing of daily reports.
- Participated in the day to day planning of the production schedule.

EDUCATION

2012 - 2016

Bachelor of Science in Food Science & Technology ,University of Nairobi (Hons)

2007 - 2010

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education, St. Francis Rang'ala Girls High School (A-)

CORE QUALIFICATIONS

- Trained ISO 22000 internal auditor
- Food Safety Management Systems HACCP ISO 22000:2005
 Implementation and 9001:2015
- Environmental Management systems ISO14001:2015& and knowledgeable of Occupational Health and Safety ISO45001

REFERENCES

Titus Churchill Jura, Production Manager, Trufoods Limited PO Box 41521 00100 Nairobi

Tel: +254723516817

Email: jurohills@gmail.com

Judy Waithera Kanyatte, Category Manager, UNSOS P O Box 42082 00100 Nairobi, Tel: +254720615947

Email: kanyatte@un.org

Gabriel Otieno, University lecturer, USIU-Africa P O Box 14634 00800 Nairobi

Tel:+254722805371 Email: gokello@usiu.ac.ke